<resources>

    <string name="app_name">Turismo_Vedra</string>
    
    <!--    Menú Principal-->
    <string name="turismoVedra">VEDRA TOURISM</string>
    <string name="logoVedra">icon Vedra</string>
    <string name="menuHamburguesa">hamburger menu button</string>
    <string name="informacionTuristica">Tourist information</string>
    <string name="informacionTuristica1">TOURIST INFORMATION</string>
    <string name="webVedra">www.concellodevedra.es</string>
    <string name="comoChegar">HOW TO GET THERE</string>
    <string name="contacto">CONTACT</string>
    <string name="mapaTuristico">TOURIST MAP</string>
    <string name="telefonosInteres">USEFUL TELEPHONE NUMBERS</string>
    <string name="textoInicio">I am the municipality of Vedra and I am located in the heart of the Ulla Valley, in the southern part of the province of A Coruña. I have an area of 53km2 and a population of 5100 inhabitants who live in my 12 parishes.
\n\nA walk through my natural landscapes will immerse yourself in a place with personality. It is not possible to stand out just one place or monument. Everything deserves to be discovered.
\n\nFor that and more…I am Vedra!</string>

    <string name="nonoPodesPerder">NOT TO BE MISSED...</string>

    <string name="distancia">Distancia</string>
    <string name="descargaPDFrutas">Descarga PDF Rutas de Senderismo </string>

    <string name="senderoLineal">Tipo de sendero: Lineal</string>
    <string name="senderoCircular">Tipo de sendero: Circular</string>
    <string name="duracion">Duración aproximada</string>
    <string name="duracionIda">Duración aproximada (ida)</string>
    <string name="dificultadeMedia">Dificultad: media</string>
    <string name="datosTecnicos">Datos técnicos</string>


    <string name="si">Si</string>
    <string name="no">No</string>


    <string name="textoRutas1">Caminar por el placer de conocer, recorrer caminos salpicados de historia, cultura, tradiciones... y moldeados por la fuerza de la naturaleza. Gozar del paisaje.
        \n\nComo pueden comprobar Vedra abre sus puertas de par en par al caminante, para mostrar una tierra cariñosa, sencilla, donde los senderos muestran la belleza y la diversidad del ayuntamiento.
        \n \n*Para equiparse hay que tener en cuenta la época del año en la que se hacen las rutas.</string>

    <string name="textoRutas2">Si continuamos nuestro recorrido, llegaremos al entorno de la Ferreira, y finalizaremos esta ruta en Ponte Busacos, punto más destacable por su valor histórico; por el transcurrió la IV Vía Militar romana que unía Brácara (Braga) e Astúrica (Astorga); y en la actualidad discurre la Vía de la Plata del Camino de Santiago.</string>


    <string name="textoRutas3">El inicio de este sendero se sitúa en la parroquia de Vedra, junto al puente de la carretera principal que atraviesa el río Pereiro. Se accede partiendo de la casa del Ayuntamiento en dirección a Illobre, a mitad de camino encontramos un panel de ruta (punto de partida).
        \n \nEsta ruta nos conduce paralelos al río Pereiro, y nos permite descubrir toda una serie de molinos, salpicados aquí y allá, alguno de ellos aún hoy en funcionamiento. A poucos Kilómetros río arriba localízase a fervenza do Pereiro que con su ruído rompe el silencio del paisaje.</string>


    <string name="textoRutas4">Además de conocer la cultura molinera, también podemos observar las tareas agrícolas en prados, huertos y viñedos.
        \n \nLa ruta nos lleva a través del bosque por estrechos caminos rodeados de vegetación y cascadas que con su melodía hacen más grato el caminar.</string>
    <string name="textoRutas5">El punto de partida se sitúa en la parroquia de San Pedro de Vilanova. Nos desviamos de la carretera N-525 Santiago-Ourense en dirección a la iglesia parroquial y, dejando atrás esta, giramos primero a la izquierda y después a la derecha, siguiendo las indicaciones viarias.
        \n \nEsta ruta nos muestra un conjunto etnográfico formado por varios molinos en buen estado de conservación que siguen el curso del río de Merín, acercandonos a una constante en el paisaje de Vedra que nos da idea de la importancia que la agricultura tuvo en la economía de nuestros antepasados, y del fuerte vínculo que liga por siempre esta tierra al agua.</string>
    <string name="textoRutas6">La primera parada a destacar es el casco tradicional del pueble de Ponte Ulla. A poca distancia nos encontramos en nuestro camino con un molino de singulares características, el molino de Reboredo, provisto de cinco muelas. \n \nLa siguiente parada será en el área de recreo de Agronovo, donde podremos descansar un rato para reponer fuerzas.
        \n \nContinuamos hasta llegar al área de recreo del Coto de Ximonde, un de los cotos de salmón más importantes de Galicia, convertido hoy en una estación ictiológica de cría y reproducción.
        \n \nMás adelante nos espera el área de recreo de Cubelas, que pone punto y final a este hermoso recorrido por el Ulla.</string>
    <string name="textoRutas7">Su inicio se localiza en el Mirador de Gundián, junto al puente del ferrocarril. Para llegar hasta el mirador se toma la salida de la carretera N-525 Santiago-Ourense en el lugar de Ponte Ulla.
        \n \nEl Mirador de Gundián está situado a unos 100 metros sobre el nivel del río, que permite una visión incomparable del Ulla estrechándose en el paso da Cova, bajo el puente del ferrocarril, y continuando luego su recorrido hasta perderse a lo lejos.
        \n \nEsta ruta discurre por el margen derecho del río Ulla aprovechando caminos de paso, sendas de pescadores y senderos ya marcados.</string>


    <string name="distanciaRutaPereiro">Distancia: 5 Km</string>
    <string name="inicioRutaPereiro">Inicio: Puente de Pereiro-Carretera</string>
    <string name="finalizacionRutaPereiro">Finalización: Puente Busacos</string>
    <string name="duracionRutaPereiro">2 h 15 min </string>
    <string name="nomeRutaPereiro">Ruta do Pereiro</string>


    <string name="distanciaRutaMolinos">Distancia: 2 Km</string>
    <string name="inicioRutaMolinos">Inicio: Área de Interpretación de los Molinos \n42º46.433´N 008º26.629´W</string>
    <string name="duracionRutaMolinos">1 h 10 min</string>
    <string name="nomeRutaMolinos">Ruta de los Molinos</string>


    <string name="distanciaRutaSanXoan">Distancia: 11,2 Km</string>
    <string name="inicioRutaSanXoan">Inicio: Mirador de Gundian \42º47.117´N 008º23.700´W</string>
    <string name="finalizacionRutaSanXoan">Finalización: Área de recreo de Cubelas \42º44.754´N 008º28.331´W</string>
    <string name="duracionRutaSanXoan">5 h 20 min</string>
    <string name="nomeRutaSanXoan">Ruta de San Xoán da Cova</string>


    <string name="infoComoChegar">There are diferent ways to reach Vedra:
        \n\nFrom Santiago de Compostela, taking the N-525 towards Ourense you will cross directly into the area of Vedra.
        \n\nThe N-525 Santiago-Ourense A-road and the AC.241 A Ponte Ulla-Pontevea B-road come together in A Ponte Ulla.
        \n\nAnother option is to take the toll motorway AP-53 Santiago-Ourense and come off at the first exit (Ribadulla: A Ponte Ulla, P.K.14).\n\n
All of the hamlets and villages in Vedra are linked by B-roads.
        \n\nTwo bus companies (Monbús and Seoane) run services linking each of the parishes with Santiago.</string>
    <string name="distanciasKmPorEstrada">Distances by road:</string>
    <string name="santiago">Santiago de Compostela</string>
    <string name="pontevedra">Pontevedra</string>
    <string name="aCoruña">A Coruña</string>
    <string name="ourense">Ourense</string>
    <string name="vigo">Vigo</string>
    <string name="ferrol">Ferrol</string>
    <string name="lugo">Lugo</string>
    <string name="kmSantiago">16 Km</string>
    <string name="kmPontevedra">70 Km</string>
    <string name="kmCoruña">86 Km</string>
    <string name="kmOurense">92 Km</string>
    <string name="kmVigo">97 Km</string>
    <string name="kmFerrol">108 Km</string>
    <string name="kmLugo">115 Km</string>

    <string name="casaDosPeons">Municipal Dynamization and Promotion Center "Casa dos Peóns-Centro Visitantes"</string>
    <string name="direccionPeons">Picón nº2, San Pedro de Vilanova\nEstrada N-524, P.K. 326 –\n42º47.418´N 008º26.650´W</string>
    <string name="telefonoPeons">981512482 - 981814612</string>
    <string name="mailPeons">casadospeons@concellodevedra.com</string>
    <string name="oficinaPeregrinos">Pilgrims Office</string>
    <string name="direccionPeregrinos">Rectoral de A Ponte Ulla</string>
    <string name="telefonoPeregrinos">981512482 - 981814612</string>
    <string name="mailPeregrinos">www.concellodevedra.com\nwww.vedraturismo.com</string>

    <!--    Que facer-->
    <string name="queFacer">WHAT TO DO</string>
    <string name="actividadesSociais">Social activities and local parties</string>

    <string name="actividadesDeportivas">Sport activities</string>
    <string name="camino">Camino de Santiago</string>
    <string name="actividadesRelixiosas">Religious activities</string>

    <string name="festasGastronomicas">Gastronomic festivals</string>

    <string name="xeneraisUlla">Xenerais da Ulla</string>
    <string name="rutaCamelia">The Route of de Camellie</string>
    <string name="festasRelixiosas">Fiestas religiosas</string>

    <string name="calendario">Schedule</string>
    <string name="xaneiro">Xaneiro</string>
    <string name="febreiro">Febreiro</string>
    <string name="marzo">Marzo</string>
    <string name="abril">Abril</string>
    <string name="maio">Maio</string>
    <string name="xuno">Xuño</string>
    <string name="xullo">Xullo</string>
    <string name="agosto">Agosto</string>
    <string name="setembro">Setembro</string>
    <string name="outubro">Outubro</string>
    <string name="novembro">Novembro</string>
    <string name="decembro">Decembro</string>

    <string name="festXan1">Festas Patronais a primeira fin de semana despois do día de Reis en San Xián de Sales.</string>
    <string name="festFeb1">Ceremonia das Candeas o 2 de febreiro en San Pedro de Sarandon</string>
    <string name="festFeb2">San Blas o domingo seguinte ó 3 de febreiro en San Mamede de Ribadulla</string>
    <string name="festAbr1">Virxe das Angustias o domingo de Pascua en Illobre</string>
    <string name="festMaio1">San Pedro Mártir o domingo seguinte ó 29 de abril en Merin.</string>
    <string name="festMaio2">Santa Cruz o 3 de maio en Santa Cruz de Ribadulla.</string>
    <string name="festXun1">Santísimo en San Xián de Sales</string>
    <string name="festXun2">Santa Isabel o segundo domingo despois de Corpus en San Fins de Sales.</string>
    <string name="festXun3">San Pedro o 29 e 30 de xuño en San Pedro de Sarandon.</string>
    <string name="festXun4">S. Pedro a primeira fin de semana tralo 29 dese mes en San Pedro de Vilanova.</string>
    <string name="festXul1">Concepción o primeiro domingo de xullo en San Pedro de Sarandon.</string>
    <string name="festXul2">San Cristovo o primeiro domingo despois do 10 de xullo en Merin.</string>
    <string name="festXul3">O Carme o domingo seguinte ó 16 de xullo en Trobe</string>
    <string name="festXul4">Festas da Madalena o 22 e 23 de xullo en A Ponte Ulla</string>
    <string name="festAgo1">Festas Patronais o 1, 2 e 3 de agosto en San Fins de Sales.</string>
    <string name="festAgo2">Festas Patronais o 7 e 8 de agosto en San Mamede de Ribadulla.</string>
    <string name="festAgo3">San Campio o  9, 10 e 11 de agosto en San Miguel de Sarandon.</string>
    <string name="festAgo4">Santiaguiño o sábado anterior ó último domingo de agosto en San Pedro de Vilanova.</string>
    <string name="festAgo5">Romaría dos Remedios o derradeiro domingo de agosto en Trobe</string>
    <string name="festSet1">As Dores o primeiro domingo de setembro en Vedra</string>
    <string name="festSet2">Romaría do Gundián-Procesión e Fogos de artificio o 7 e 8  de setembro en A Ponte Ulla</string>
    <string name="festSet3">Romaría do Patio o luns despois do terceiro domingo de setembro en Santa Cruz de Ribadulla.</string>
    <string name="festSet4">San Miguel o 29 de setembro en San Miguel de Sarandon.</string>
    <string name="festNov1">Santo André o 30 de novembro en Illobre</string>
    <string name="festDec1">Santa Baia o 10 de decembro en Vedra</string>

    <string name="festAbrGastronomica1">A Exaltación do viño da Ulla, no mes de abril en San Miguel de Sarandón.</string>
    <string name="festMaioGastronomica1">A festa da Orella de Porco, no mes de maio en San Fins de Sales.</string>
    <string name="festMaioGastronomica2">A Festa do Porco á Brasa, no mes de maio en Trobe</string>
    <string name="festMaioGastronomica3">A Festa do Carneiro ó espeto, no mes de maio en San Xián de Sales</string>
    <string name="festMaioGastronomica4">Fiesta de la Aguardiente, en el mes de mayo en San Mamede de Ribadulla.</string>
    <string name="festXulGastronomica1">A Festa do Escalo, no mes de xullo en Santa Cruz de Ribadulla.</string>


    <string name="caminoMinotoRibeiro">Way of St James-Miñoto-Ribeiro</string>
    <string name="caminoMinotoRibeiroDescricion">Este antigo camiño discorría dende o norte de Portugal ata a cidade do Apóstolo, atravesando zonas das provincias de Ourense e Pontevedra, e entrando na Coruña pola Ponte de Sarandón, no Concello de Vedra. Ao longo da historia, esta ruta medieval ademais de ser ruta de peregrinación foi utilizada polos arrieiros para levar o viño do Ribeiro a Compostela. Polo tanto, este camiño deixou unha pegada de grande significado e transcendencia tanto no comercio como no relixioso na Idade Media e na Idade Moderna. Abundan os documentos históricos que fan mención a este itinerario.
        \n\nEste Camiño existe dende sempre, pero aínda non é oficial, ou sexa, aínda non está recoñecido como Camiño de Santiago polos estamentos oficiais eclesiásticos nin civís, aínda que en 1783 o arcebispo de Santiago pedíalle ao rexedor do Ribeiro que arranxara determinados puntos deste camiño para que poideran pasar mellor por el “peregrinos, viajeros y comerciantes”, como consta nos libros existentes no Arquivo Histórico Provincial de Ourense, Municipal de Ribadavia (sito no Museo de Ribadavia).
        Por este motivo, formouse unha Asociación no ano 2014 coa finalidade de acadar o seu nomeamento oficial, e na que se unen persoas de estamentos públicos (concellos das provincias de Ourense, Pontevedra e A Coruña, e tamén de Portugal) e privados, organismos e asociacións; cunha finalidade común: visibilizar este Camiño, promocionalo, e que todo iso sirva para mellorar a calidade de vida desta zona e dos seus habitantes.
        \n\nNo ano 2017, o Concello de Vedra desenvolveu un campo de traballo para realizar o marcado do mesmo no tramo do municipio.  O Camiño entra no territorio vedrés pola Ponte de Sarandón e discorre pola aldea de Corbeixe (San Mamede de Ribadulla) ata o portalón do Pazo de Ximonde. De aquí atravesa Silva de Arriba (San Miguel de Sarandón) por camiños secundarios ata chegar a aldea de Sarandón. O último tramo localízase nas parroquias de Merín (Chao de Cartas) e Vilanova.</string>

    <string name="caminoViaPrata">Way of St James-Silver Way</string>
    <string name="caminoViaPrataDescricion1">Todo aquel que se achegue ata o Concello de Vedra debe saber que polas súas terras discorre unha das vías de peregrinación que conducen a Compostela, a coñecida como Camiño Real ou Vía da Prata. Esta última etiqueta, hoxe en día a máis estendida, provén da idea de que este camiño é a prolongación da calzada romana denominada Vía da Prata, que comunicaba Mérida e Astorga cruzando de sur a norte o oeste peninsular, e que, trala desaparición da estructura administrativa romana, foi aproveitada como vía de peregrinación a Compostela.
    \n \nEsta Vía fai a súa entrada en terras de Vedra pola Ponte Ulla, e dende aquí atravesa varios lugares ata chegar á aldea de Outeiro, na veciña parroquia de Vilanova. Aquí cómpre facermos un alto no camiño para poder observar con atención a capela do Santiaguiño que data do século XVIII.
    \n \nXunto a ela hai unha fonte barroca que sobresae polo seu valor lendario, e que foi trasladada alí no ano 1724 dende un lugar máis alto. Ten unha inscrición que fala do traslado do corpo do apóstolo Santiago e un relevo que representa parte da lenda do Dragón, relacionada coas sagas da Raíña Lupa. No centro da fonte pode verse unha representación do apóstolo, flanqueado polos seus discípulos Teodoro e Atanasio. Segundo algúns autores estas dúas figuras procederían do antigo coro románico da Catedral de Santiago, obra do Mestre Mateo.
    \n \nA poucos metros da ermida, atopamos o último </string>
    <!--    albergue de peregrinos -->
    <string name="caminoViaPrataDescricion2">do Camiño antes de chegar a Santiago de Compostela.
    \n \nContinuamos o camiño deixando o Pico Sacro á dereita, para volver máis tarde ao territorio de Vedra e atravesar o río Pereiro por Ponte Busacos.</string>

    <string name="caminoViaPrataDescricion3">Dende alí o camiño continúa pola Susana, xa dentro do Concello de Santiago, e por Santa Lucía, Angrois e Sar. A entrada da Vía da Prata na cidade faise pola porta de Mazarelos, na que hai unha alusión a esta terra da Ulla, nunha inscrición que fala da chegada a través dela dos viños da Ulla.</string>
    <string name="albergue">albergue de peregrinos de Vedra</string>
    <string name="albergueMaiusculas">Albergue de peregrinos de Vedra</string>

    <string name="descargaAlquilerBici">Download PDF: Rent a BTT bike</string>
    <string name="descargaPDFcicloturismo">Download PDF: Cycling route through Val do Ulla</string>

    <string name="senderismo">Hiking</string>
    <string name="pescaFluvial">River fishing</string>
    <string name="piraguismo">Canoeing</string>
    <string name="cicloturismo">Cycling</string>
    <string name="etnoturismo">Ethnotourism</string>

    <!--    Que ver-->
    <string name="queVer">WHAT TO SEE</string>

    <string name="cabeceraAgronovo">Agronovo Recreational Area</string>
    <string name="agronovo">The Agronovo Recreational Area is located at the foot of the River Ulla, near the San Xoán da Cova trekking route. It is equipped with a swimming area, tables and benches, toilets, barbecue area… \n\nA chub fishing competition is held here on the second Sunday in July, accompanied by an extensive festive programme.</string>

    <string name="cabeceraCubelas">Cubelas Recreational Area</string>
    <string name="cubelas">The Cubelas Recreational Area is located at the foot of the River Ulla, about 300 metres from Ximonde Preserve. It is the start and finish point of the San Xoán da Cova trekking route. \n\nThis area is equipped with tables and benches. It also features a small botanical garden with riverside flora species found in the Ulla-Deza River System, wich is part of the Natura 2000 Network.</string>

    <string name="cabeceraMiradorGundian">Gundián Viewpoint</string>
    <string name="miradorGundian">The Gundián Viewpoint provides views of a magnificent natural setting. What stands out first of all is Paso da Cova, which arises when the south slope of Pico Sacro, which features a 4-kilometre-long vein of quartz, is cut through by the River Ulla, with Monte Castro on the other side. The result is an unique and singular site, a magnificent narrowing of the river down to 4 metres wide between two vertical 50-metre-high walls along a distance of 14 metres. This pass is now crossed by a railway bridge, the Old Gundián bridge and a modern bridge for the high-speed AVE train; it stands out as the only terrain south of the River Ulla belonging to the province of A Coruña. \n\nAccording to different legends, there used to be a large lagoon upriver. As the story goes, hidden among the rocks near the present-day Paso da Cova, there was a 14th century monastery of the Templars (of which no trace remains). Tradition adds that the monks of this monastery of San Xoán da Cova perforated the mountain to empty the lagoon, thereby giving rise to this narrow pass. \n\nToday, both the Gundián Viewpoint and the Campo de Gundián Recreational Area enable us to enjoy this marvellous natural setting.</string>

    <string name="cabeceraCampoGundian">Campo de Gundián Recreational Area</string>
    <string name="campoGundian">The Campo de Gundián Recreational Area is made up of a singular ensemble featuring a chapel, fountain, bandstand, tables and benches overlooking the River Ulla, as well as the old Gundián Bridge and modern AVE (high-speed rail) Bridge, enabling visitors to enjoy this magnificent natural setting. \n\nThe area’s location stands out as the only terrain south of the River Ulla that belongs to A Coruña province. Here is where the famous procession of Nosa Señora de Gundián is held on September 7, in which Our Lady is carried out of the village accompanied by a large fireworks display. \n\nThe Gundián Viewpoint is also located in the surroundings, featuring magnificent views of the entire region.</string>

    <string name="cabeceraCoutoXimonde">Ximonde Preserve Recreational Area</string>
    <string name="coutoXimonde">Ximonde is one of the most important salmon preserves in Galicia. The fishermen’s shelter houses a small River Ulla interpretation centre and a fish-breeding and –reproduction station. \n\nThe Recreational Area stands out above all to its fishing posts, waterfall and especially its hanging bridge. It is an ideal place for walking and enjoying nature.</string>

    <string name="cabeceraPazoSantaCruzRibadulla">Pazo de Santa Cruz de Ribadulla</string>
    <string name="pazoSantaCruzRibadulla">The Pazo de Santa Cruz de Rivadulla, in a beautiful setting on the shores of the Ulla Valley protected by the peak Sacro. \n\nBack in the 16th century, the property was walled and divided following a renaissance design by planting more than 500 Olive trees and vines. Fountains, ponds, the waterfall, the house and the chapel were also placed and enhanced.\n\nMost of the rustic landscape garden we see today was largely developed by the Armada family in the 1870s.  It is a remarkable relic: a picturesque pleasure ground of winding paths and sinuous waterways, and romantic huts. \n\nIt is currently the reference in Galicia for the outstanding collections of Camellia Trees, boxwood alleys, giant magnolias and Liriodendrons as well as Palm trees, australian ferns, Cryptomerias and oak trees.</string>

    <string name="cabeceraPuenteGundian">Gundian Bridge</string>
    <string name="puenteGundian1">One of the reasons for the delay in the railway link between A Coruña and the rest of the Meseta was the intricate Galician orography. One of the greatest difficulties was the construction of the bridge that would join the quartz massif of the Pico Sacro del Paso de A Cova, over the river Ulla, in the municipality of Vedra. To this end, a large 167-meter-long bridge was designed in the 1930s that contained a large arch with a span of 52 metres. However, it was not until 1958 when it was finished off. It is called Ponte Gundián.</string>
    <string name="puenteGundian2">The bridge is currently still used by the train, although it has been enabled for your enjoyment and for this reason it can be crossed from the viewpoint or accessed from the other side, along the track that comes from the Gundián Chapel. Thanks to the spectacular natural setting where it is located and its 90 meters high, Ponte Gundián is usually used by lovers of extreme sports such as "bungee jumping".</string>
    <string name="puenteGundian3">We must know that both the Gundián Bridge and the new viaduct are entirely in the province of A Coruña, since this is the only territory south of the Ulla that belongs to that province.</string>

    <string name="cabeceraPuenteAVEGundian">Gundián AVE Bridge</string>
    <string name="puenteAVEGundian">The Ministry of Public Works, through the Adif entity, began the construction of a new Ulla viaduct, one of the constructions included in the Silleda (Dornelas)-Vedra-Boqueijón subsection, of the Orense-Santiago de Compostela axis of the North Corridor- high-speed northwest, which is part of the L.A.V. Olmedo - Zamora - Galicia. \n\nThe new bridge, which starts just 130 m from the Gundián bridge, was built in 2008. It is a unique structure over 1 km long, which is considered to be of architectural interest in Spain. The uniqueness of this work and the complexity and originality of its construction made the Galician Association of Civil Engineers, Canals and Ports award it the San Telmo Prize in 2011, with which this group distinguishes the most representative civil works in Galicia. carried out during the year prior to its call.</string>

    <string name="cabeceraPuenteColganteXimonde">Puente colgante de Ximonde</string>
    <string name="puenteColganteXimonde">In the winter of 2000, a strong flood caused the old footbridge located over the Ulla River - built in 1970 and replaced in the 80s - to be demolished. For this reason, in 2012 the creation of a new suspension bridge was planned in the same place, which has had a significant impact on the environment. With a length of about 87 meters and a height of another 8 meters above the river, the Ximonde flyover allows only the transit of pedestrians, is accessible for the disabled and has a non-slip surface.\n\nThe works for the development allowed to recover the paths adjacent to the river that joined the different fishing posts. Crossing the bridge towards A Estrada there is also a small recreational area equipped with tables and benches to rest after a day surrounded by nature, although there are other areas scattered along the riverbank. In addition, the Ximonde suspension bridge is the starting point, or part of the way, of different hiking trails in the area. \n\nTo give an example, the approved path PR-G36 of San Xoán da Cova runs downstream crossing this elevated area, but there are many other routes that run through the bulk of the Ulla River between walkways, fishing grounds, recreational areas and other special spaces. interest. For lovers of hiking, routes such as the one that goes from the famous Gundián viewpoint to the Ximonde preserve on a linear route; the one that departs from the Ximonde fishing area towards the Sarandón bridge; or the one that runs through this area over the Ulla to the Santeles preserve in just 4.5 kilometres, are some of the best options to enjoy the surroundings.</string>

    <string name="cabeceraMolinoReboredo">Reboredo Mill</string>
    <string name="molinoReboredo">The mill or Muíño de Reboredo we find a maquía mill owned by Adolfo Peiteado, of which there is documentation dating from 1840. The most characteristic thing is that it has 5 grinding stones or moas in separate compartments, and in the last of the compartments there are 2 mills: one of sulfur and another albeiro. The sulfur mill was used for this product, which was used to make gunpowder; hence the well-known pyrotechnic tradition of the Ponte Ulla parish. The albeiro mill or muíño had a different stone, called albeira stone, and was used to grind wheat or rye, obtaining a whiter flour, which is why the term albeiro refers to “alba”. \n\nThis mill stopped working almost 40 years ago, around the time the Portodemouros reservoir opened. The neighbors remember that next to it there was an old fishery. \n\nIn the parish of Vilanova, the municipality of de Vedra has an interpretation area for the mills where the parts, the operation and the different types of mills are explained according to their structure. From the interpretation area, a recommendable circular route begins next to the Merín River.</string>

    <string name="CabeceiraIgrexaFonteCruceiroVedra">Church, fountain and stone cross of Vedra</string>
    <string name="igrexaFonteCruceiroVedra">The parish church of Santa Eulalia de Vedra is located on a high spot dominating the entire valley, accompanied by a stone cross and a fountain at the foot of the atrium. It is worth mentioning the main chapel’s altarpiece from the end of the 18th century made by Jose Gambino. He also made the image of Santa Eulalia, the patron saint of the parish. The other two altarpieces are slightly older and were made by Francisco de Moas, who belonged to the school of Miguel de Romai. They are found in the two chapels at the sides of the naves and their main themes are the “Virgen de los Dolores” or “Virgen de la Soledad” in one case, and Christ tied to the column, accompanied by other images, in the other. The historian and archaeologist López Ferreiro was the parish priest in this church from 1866 to 1871.</string>

    <string name="cabeceraCapillaFuenteSANTIAGUIÑO">Chapel and fountain of Santiaguiño</string>
    <string name="capillaFuenteSANTIAGUIÑO">The chapel of Santiago, located in the village of Outeiro in the parish of San Pedro de Vilanova, was built in the 18th century. \n\nBeside it is a small baroque fountain that was moved to its current location from a spot higher up in 1724. It features, sculpted in relief, the legend of the Dragon, related to the sagas of Queen Lupa. It also bears an inscription describing the transfer of the Apostle James’ body. At the centre of the fountain there is a representation of the Apostle with his disciples Teodoro and Atanasio. According to some authors, these two figures came from Santiago Cathedral’s former Romanesque choir, made by Maestro Mateo. \n\nA few metres from the chapel, we find the last hostel on the “Vía de la Plata” Route before reaching Santiago de Compostela</string>

    <string name="cabeceiraRoteiroEmigracion">Emigration route</string>
    <string name="roteiroEmigracion">Each emigrant from Vedra, and foron milleiros, opened a new path for himself, for his family and for his land. Part of what we are now is the disastrous result of immigration to America. A massive emigration that left its landscape link in works of unmistakable size, built, for the most part, at the first goal of the 20th century, bordered by the sea. \n\nO Roteiro da Emigración is an interpretive itinerary that signals and links the places of the council where some of the most worthy collective works of our history can be found: the schools, cemeteries, paths and bridges promoted, with large doses of love to the land, to which they cover the educational centers. by the societies of emigrants from Vedra in Bos Aires.</string>

    <!--    Onde comer -->
    <string name="ondeComer">WHERE TO EAT</string>

    <string name="restaurantes">RESTAURANTES</string>
    <string name="cafeteria">BARES E CAFETERÍAS</string>

    <string name="vedra"><u>Sarandón - Vedra - Trobe - San Mamede</u></string>
    <string name="santacruz"><u>Santa Cruz - Ponte Ulla</u></string>
    <string name="sanfins"><u>Illobre - San Fins - San Xián</u></string>


    <!--    Onde durmir -->
    <string name="ondeDurmir">WHERE TO SLEEP</string>


    <!--    Productores locais -->
    <string name="produtoresLocais">LOCAL PRODUCERS</string>
    <string name="adegas">WINE CELLARS</string>
    <string name="destileria">FIREWATER AND LIQUOR DISTILLERIES</string>
    <string name="froitasVerduras">FRUITS AND VEGETABLES</string>
    <string name="viveiros">PLANT NURSERIES</string>
    <string name="panaderias">BAKERIES</string>
    <string name="producciondeaceite">OIL PRODUCTION</string>
    <string name="artesania">CRAFTWORK</string>
    <string name="deseno">DESIGN</string>
    <string name="tocados">HEADDRESS</string>
    <string name="pirotecnias">FIREWORKS FACTORIES</string>
    <string name="Benvidos">Welcome!</string>

    <string name="descricionPesca">El ayuntamiento de Vedra forma parte del territorio que constituye Área de Santiago, grupo de dieciseis ayuntamientos de la zona de Santiago de Compostela que trabajamos en la promoción turística conjunta y que abarca el sur de la provincia de A Coruña y el norte de la provincia de Pontevedra, separadas ambas por el río Ulla, que hace de frontera natural.
        \n \nPrecisamente, uno de los principales elementos que definen este territorio es la presencia de dos de los principales recursos hídricos de Galicia,tanto por caudal como por su riqueza natural, paisajistica e incluso cultural: el Sistema Fluvial Ulla-Deza, del que forma parte nuetro ayuntamiento, y que delimita por el sur, y el río Tambre y sus afluentes, que la demarcan por el norte.
        \n \nLa riqueza piscícola (truchas, salmones, lampreas, reos y escalos) se conjugan en este entorno con una variada fauna y flora, compuesta por plantas y árboles de ribera y especies acuáticas de gran vistosidad, pero también la existencia de un importante patrimonio desconocido de molinos, pesqueras, represas, senderos, etc, de indudable interés para viajeros interesados en el conocimiento del medio natural.
        \n \nAsí, el objetivo general de Área de
        Santiago es fomentar el aprovechamiento turístico de nuestros ríos, a través de la práctica de deportes fluviales: principalmente pesca
        (pero también senderismo fluvial – como ejemplo el proyecto “Goza do Ulla” que iniciamos hace unos años-, el rafting, descenso en kayak,
        piragüismo, etc.) y de su patrimonio natural y cultural asociado (molinos, represas, puentes, etc.)
        \n \nPor eso, durante los últimos meses de 2014
        desde Área de Santiago venimos trabajando en la configuración del producto turístico de pesca fluvial, tanto en la información que necesita el
        visitante pescador como en la formación del sector turístico relacionado, en este caso establecimientos de turismo rural que actúan como
        anfitriones.
         \n \nEn este sentido, la página web de Área de Santiago cuenta ya con una sección específica de Pesca Fluvial
        (www.areasantiago.es/pesca-fluvial ) en tres idiomas (gallego, español e inglés) en la que los visitantes pescadores pueden encontrar
        información precisa sobre los ríos, las áreas de pesca, la tramitación de permisos y licencias y los alojamientos de turismo rural que por su
        proximidad, sus características o su cariño al río, están especialmente recomendadas para los amantes de la pesca y el turismo fluvial,
        alojamientos todos que entre finales de 2014 y principios de 2015, mostraron su interés por trabajar en este producto turístico vinculado
        a la pesca fluvial, para firmar el correspondiente compromiso de adhesión.
        \n \nAsí mismo, Área de Santiago acaba de publicar la primera guía
        informativa sobre la pesca fluvial que se edita en Galicia en clave turística, en la que se recogen aspectos de interés para este tipo de
        turistas pescadores, como trámites y permisos, modalidades de pesca, especies, zonas de pesca recomendadas e informaciones prácticas,
         alojamientos adheridos al proyecto y otras informaciones complementarias.

         \n \nEsta primera edición de la guía, que se actualizará anualmente coincidiendo con el inicio de la temporada de pesca, estará disponible
        on-line en tres idiomas (gallego, español e inglés) en la sección de pesca de la web anteriormente
        indicada www.areasantiago.es/pesca-fluvial
         \n \nTambién en estos días, Área de Santiago está llevando a cabo el Famtrip/Presstrip de Pesca Fluvial
        con el objetivo de dar a conocer a deportistas de élite, medios especializados y turoperadores las potencialidades de nuestro territorio como
        destino de turismo de pesca fluvial.
        \n \nÁrea de Santiago trata de fomentar la práctica de este deporte de río en su modalidad de captura y suelta
        (pesca sin muerte), para evitar la sobre explotación de nuestros cursos fluviales y la necesaria sostenibiliad medioambiental</string>
    <string name="descargaPDFGuiaPesca">Download here the River Fishing Guide</string>


</resources>